coastalscents.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy

Thank you for accessing the CoastalScents.com Website (“Site”) operated by K-Plex, LLC. We respect your privacy and want to protect your personal information. To learn more, please read this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, use, and (under certain conditions) disclose your personal information. This Privacy Policy also explains the steps we have taken to secure your personal information. Finally, this Privacy Policy explains your options regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of your personal information. By visiting the Site directly or through another site, you accept the practices described in this Policy.

This privacy policy applies to the Site. This privacy policy does not necessarily apply to any offline collection of your personal information. Please see below for details.

**We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices on any website not operated by K-Plex, LLC to which the Site links or that links to the Site.**

Coastal Scents collects personal information when you subscribe to our Newsletter, create an account, accept push messages, and when you make a purchase. However, we do not sell, rent, or share any personal information that you have provided to us with individuals or companies. All information collected on this site will be kept strictly confidential.

We do not store your credit card information on our server and/or keep credit cards on file. Therefore, if you reorder, you will be asked for your credit card information again. Although some websites do offer express checkout and save your credit card information to your account, we chose not to offer this option to provide our customers with the best protection and security possible.

To be able to access your account, you must enter your email address and password. This is to establish your personal identity and respond with relevant account information. If there is a problem with your order, we may use your name, email address, or phone number to contact you.

We may need to disclose user information in certain exceptional circumstances. This may be needed to protect against illegal hackers, our legal rights, or to address actual/threatened illegal or harmful conduct. Disclosure may also be required by legal process, such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order. Transfer of ownership or operations of the site may require disclosure of customer data.

You can access and manage your account information at any time once logged into our website. Certain information, such as name or address, can be updated or corrected.

Please note that in order to provide better functionality to our users, Coastalscents.com employs cookies, which are used to maintain your shopping cart status. Our credit card and payment processors may also collect information from you in order to be able to process your payments. If you have any questions, please feel free to contact our Customer Service Department.

Coastal Scents is GDPR compliant and will process your personal date requests within 30 days.

Once you have placed your order, you agree to all the terms, conditions, and shipping policies of Coastalscents.com/K-Plex, LLC.  

Coastal Scents reserves the right to change any prices and descriptions without prior notice. We reserve the right, at any time, without notice and in our sole discretion, to terminate or reject any order and to block or prevent your future access to and use of coastalscents.com.

We make no warranties or representations whatsoever regarding the quality, content, completeness, suitability, adequacy, sequence, accuracy, or timeliness of any information and data on this website.  

We shall not in any event be liable for any direct, indirect, punitive, special, incidental, or consequential damages. This includes, but is not limited to, lost revenue or lost profits arising out of or in anyway connected with the use or misuse of the information or lack of information on this website.

By accessing our web pages, you assume all risks associated with the use of this site. Thus including any risk to your computer, software, or data being damaged by any virus, software, or any other file, which may be transmitted or activated via a web page or your access to it. 

K-Plex, LLC/Coastal Scents is not responsible for any use or misuse of purchases made from coastalscents.com. In addition, we are not responsible for recipes, formulas, or finished products, which do not turn out as expected by the customer. Fragrance and Essential Oils must be kept away from children and pets and are not to be used undiluted on the skin. You alone are responsible for product and recipe testing to ensure compatibility and safety. Our products are for cosmetic purposes only and not intended for human consumption. 

**Please contact our Customer Service Department should you have any further questions or concerns by email using our Contact Us link or by phone: (909) 297-5435** **. Our Customer Service Department is available 24 hours per day, seven days a week.

We value all of our customers and look forward to assisting you.

**

**1\. Information Collection and Use**

We collect information from you in several different ways on this Site. One goal in collecting personal information from you is to provide an efficient, meaningful, and customized experience. For example, we can use your personal information to:

  * help make the Site faster and easier for you to use by not having to enter information more than once. 
  * help you quickly find information, products, and services. 
  * help us create targeted content that is most appealing to you.
  * alert you to new information, products, and services that we offer.

(a) **REGISTRATION & ORDERING** Before using certain parts of any Site or ordering products, you must complete an online registration form. During registration, you will be prompted to provide to us certain personal information including, but not limited to: your name, shipping and billing address, phone number, email address, gender, and credit card number. We use this information to facilitate the transaction. In addition, we may also ask you for your country of residence and/or your organization’s country of operation, so we can comply with applicable laws and regulations. This kind of personal information is used for billing purposes, to fulfill your orders, to communicate with you about your order, and the Sites and for internal marketing purposes. If we encounter a problem when processing your order, your personal information may be used to contact you.

(b) **EMAIL ADDRESSES** Several locations of the Site permit you to enter your email address for purposes including, but not limited to: to register for a contest or sweepstakes; to request us to notify you of new makeup palettes, new products or product sizes; to sign up for email newsletters and special offers; or to sign up for the CoastalScents.com newsletter. Your participation in a contest or sweepstakes is completely voluntary, so you have a choice whether to participate and disclose information to us. We use this information to notify contest and sweepstake winners and to award prizes. We may post on the Site, the names and cities of contest and sweepstake winners. By entering a contest or sweepstakes, you may be opting-in to receive our email newsletter and special offers; this will be disclosed in the official rules governing the contest or sweepstakes. 

(c) **SMS/Text Messaging** Text Marketing and notifications (if applicable): By entering your phone number in the checkout and initializing a purchase, you agree that we may send you text notifications (for your order, including abandoned cart reminders) and text marketing offers. Text marketing messages will not exceed 10 per month. You can unsubscribe from further text messages by replying STOP. Message and data rates may apply.

(d) **COOKIES & OTHER TECHNOLOGY** Like many sites, the Site employs cookies and web beacons (also known as clear GIF technology or “action tags”) to speed your navigation of the Site, recognize you and your access privileges, and track your Site usage. 

(i) Cookies are small text files that contain a string of alphanumeric characters that remain on your hard drive until you close your browser, and persistent cookies are simply cookies that remain on your hard drive after you close your browser. Most Internet browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to refuse cookies from websites or to remove cookies from your hard drive, but if you do, you will not be able to access or use portions of the Site. We have to use cookies to enable you to select products, place them in an online shopping cart and to purchase those products. For instance, by setting a cookie on our Site, we can provide you with storage of items in your shopping cart between visits. If you do this, we keep a record of your browsing activity and purchase. THE SITE’S COOKIES DO NOT AND CANNOT INFILTRATE A USER’S HARD DRIVE TO GATHER A USER’S CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION. Our cookies are not “spyware.” 

(ii) Web beacons assist in delivering cookies and help us determine whether a web page on the Site has been viewed and, if so, how many times. For example, any electronic image on the Site, such as an ad banner, can function as a web beacon. For more information about cookies and web beacons please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/ ](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/)

(iv) As an example, Facebook collects certain information via cookies and web beacons to determine which web pages are visited or what products are purchased. Please note that any information collected by Facebook via cookies and web beacons is not linked to any customer's personal information collected by us.

(d) **LOG FILES** As is true of most websites, the Site server automatically recognizes the Internet URL from which you access the Site. We may also log your Internet protocol (“IP”) address, Internet service provider, and date/time stamp for system administration, order verification, internal marketing and system troubleshooting purposes. (An IP address may indicate the location of your computer on the Internet.)

(e) **AGE** K-Plex, LLC recognizes the particular importance of protecting the privacy of children. Consistent with the [Children's Online Privacy Protection Act](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Children%27s_Online_Privacy_Protection_Act) (COPPA), and GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR), we will not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. When a user makes a purchase on the Site, the user is representing to us that he or she is an adult. If a child provides the Site with personally identifiable information, we ask that a parent or guardian call (909) 297-5435. We will then delete the personally identifiable information pertaining to the child from our records. We do not knowingly or intentionally collect personal information from children under age 16. Elsewhere on the Site, you have represented and warranted that you are either 18 years of age or using the Site with the supervision of a parent or guardian. If you are under the age of 16, please do not submit any personal information to us, and rely on a parent or guardian to assist you.

(f) **PRODUCT REVIEWS** ** ** You may choose to submit a product review. If you submit a review, your nickname will be visible to other users (your email address will be kept private). Also, any personally identifiable information that you submit as part of the review can be read or used by other visitors to the Site. We are not responsible for any personally identifiable information that you choose to submit as part of your review. We believe you can post a quality review without disclosing any personal information.

**2\. Information Use and Disclosure**

(a) **INTERNAL USE** We use your personal information to process your order and provide you with customer service. We may internally use your personal information to improve the Sites’ content and layout, to improve outreach, for our own marketing efforts (including marketing our services and products to you), and to determine general marketplace information about visitors to the Site.

(b) **COMMUNICATIONS WITH YOU** We will use your personal information to communicate with you about the Site and your orders and deliveries. Also, we may send you an email confirmation when you [register](https://www.coastalscents.com/customer/account/create/) with us. We may send you a service-related announcement on the rare occasions when it is necessary (for example, if we must temporarily suspend our service for maintenance.) Also, you may submit your email address for reasons such as: to register for a contest or sweepstakes, to request us to notify you of new products or price changes, and to sign up for email newsletters and special offers. If you submit your email address, we use it to deliver the information to you. We always permit you to unsubscribe or opt-out of future emails (see the opt-out section, below, for more details). We will have to communicate with you about orders that you choose to place; therefore you cannot opt-out of receiving emails related to your orders.

(c) **EXTERNAL USE** We want to provide you with excellent service and to offer you a great selection. We do not sell, rent, trade, license or otherwise disclose your specific personal information or financial information to anyone except that:

(i) As do most Internet retailers, we sometimes use others to perform specific functions on our behalf. When we disclose information to these service providers, we disclose information to help them to perform their service. For example, in order to deliver products to you, we must share some information. We use third parties (such as the United States Postal Service and Federal Express) to ship products, to ensure delivery, and so that we can obtain feedback, improve the quality of our service, and measure and improve the quality of the service of the third party. In the example of shippers, we provide them with some personally identifiable information such as your name, shipping address, email, and phone number.

(ii) Similarly, to help you buy products and provide customer service to you, we must provide your credit card number to financial-services corporations such as credit-card processors and issuers. When we submit your credit card number for authorization, we use state-of-the-art data encryption to protect your information. (More on this, below, in Data Security.)

(iii) We may disclose such information in response to requests from law enforcement officials conducting investigations, subpoenas, a court order or if we are otherwise required to disclose such information by law. We will also release personal information where disclosure is necessary to protect our legal rights, enforce our Terms of Use or other agreements, or to protect others or ourselves. For example, we may share information to reduce the risk of fraud or if someone uses or attempts to use the Site for illegal reasons or to commit fraud.

(iv) We will not sell, trade or rent personally identifiable information to other companies as part of our regular course of business. However, it is possible that we might acquire, or merge with, or be acquired by another company, or that we might dispose of some or all of our assets. If that happens, your personal information may be disclosed to another company, but that disclosure will be subject to the Privacy Policy in effect.

(v) We may share non-personal information (such as the number of daily visitors to a particular web page, or the size of an order placed on a certain date) with third parties such as advertising partners. This information does not directly and personally identify you or any user.

(vi) We may publicly disclose the name, city, and state of the contest and sweepstakes winners.

The Site incorporates physical, electronic, and administrative procedures to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal information, including Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) for all financial transactions through the Site. We use SSL encryption to protect your personal information online, and we also take several steps to protect your personal information in our facilities. Access to your personal information is restricted. Only employees who need access to your personal information to perform a specific job are granted access to your personal information. Finally, we rely on third-party service providers for the physical security of some of our computer hardware. We believe that their security procedures are adequate. For example, when you visit the Site, you access servers that are kept in a secure physical environment, behind a locked cage and an electronic firewall.

While we use industry-standard precautions to safeguard your personal information, we cannot guarantee complete security. 100% complete security does not presently exist anywhere online or offline. 

**IN NO EVENT SHALL K-PLEX, LLC BE LIABLE FOR SPECIAL, INDIRECT, EXEMPLARY OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO: LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS; WITHOUT REGARD TO THE FORM OF ANY ACTION, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO: CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTIONS, ARISING OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE, COPYING OR DISPLAY OF THE CONTENTS OF THE SITE, EVEN IF COASTAL SCENTS OR AN AUTHORIZED REPRESENTATIVE OF COASTAL SCENTS HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.**

**International Users Security**

The Coastal Scents Website is hosted in the United States. If you are accessing the Coastal Scents Website or are viewing Coastal Scents Ads from the European Union, Asia, or any other region with laws or regulations governing personal data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from United States laws, please be advised that through your continued use of the Coastal Scents Website and/or viewing of Coastal Scents Ads, which is governed by U.S. law and these Privacy Policies, you are transferring your personal information to the United States and you consent to that transfer.

**Opt-Out/Corrections/Deletion**

Upon your request, we will (a) correct or update your personal information; (b) stop sending emails to your email address; and/or (c) disable your account to prevent any future purchases through that account. You can make these requests by telephoning at (909) 297-5435 or use this [Contact Us link](https://www.coastalscents.com/helpcenter). Please do not email your credit card number or other sensitive information. All data related requests will be processed within 30 days.

**Offline Collection, Use and Disclosure of Information**

The majority of information we collect is obtained through the Site, and this Privacy Policy applies only to that online collection of personal information. Personal information obtained by phone or fax is stored in our database through SSL encryption. (See the _Data Security_ section above for more information). Information received via fax is acted upon immediately, then stored in a locked depository or shredded. Offline collection, uses, and disclosures are treated consistently with our relevant online practices.

If we change or update this Privacy Policy, we will post changes and updates on the Site so that you will always be aware of what information we collect, use, and disclose. We encourage you to review this Privacy Policy from time to time, so you will know if the Privacy Policy has been changed or updated. If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy, please contact us at (909) 297-5435 or use this [Contact Us link](https://www.coastalscents.com/helpcenter).

We may assign you a password and account identification to enable you to access and use certain portions of this Site. If you use the Site, you are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of the information you submit through "My Account", the corresponding password, and for restricting access to your computer. We may assign you a password and account identification to enable you to access and use certain portions of this Site. Each time you use a password or identification, you will be deemed to be authorized to access and use the Site in a manner consistent with the terms and conditions of this Agreement and we have no obligation to investigate the authorization or source of any such access or use of the Site. 

YOU WILL BE SOLELY RESPONSIBLE FOR ALL ACCESS TO AND USE OF THIS SITE BY ANYONE USING THE PASSWORD AND IDENTIFICATION ORIGINALLY ASSIGNED TO YOU WHETHER OR NOT SUCH ACCESS TO AND USE OF THIS SITE IS ACTUALLY AUTHORIZED BY YOU, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION: ALL COMMUNICATIONS, TRANSMISSIONS AND ALL OBLIGATIONS (INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION FINANCIAL OBLIGATIONS) INCURRED THROUGH SUCH ACCESS OR USE. 

You shall immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your password or identification or any other breach or threatened breach of this Site's security.

**Responsibility for your Content**

You are solely responsible for all content that you upload, post, email, or otherwise transmit via the Site, including the submission of product ratings and reviews and all other data, profile information, documents, text, software, applications, music, sound, photographs, graphics, video, messages, ratings, forum postings, comments, questions, answers, or other materials (collectively, "Content"). We will not accept Content from you unless you are a registered user of the Site.  

**Your Use of Content on the Site and Limitation of Liability**

K-Plex, LLC is not liable for any statements, representations, or Content provided by its users in any form on the Site or any Third Party Site. Any Content, if displayed, is displayed for entertainment and informational purposes only. More generally, Content posted, via on the Site or any Third Party Site, is not controlled by K-Plex, LLC. K-Plex, LLC cannot guarantee the accuracy, integrity or quality of such Content. You understand that by using the Site, you may be exposed to Content that may be offensive, indecent, or objectionable and K-Plex, LLC shall not be liable for any such Content and that the risk of harm or damage from the foregoing rests entirely with you. Under no circumstances will K-Plex, LLC be liable in any way for any Content, including, but not limited to, for (i) any errors or omissions in any Content; or (ii) any loss or damage (including, without limitation, personal injury or property damage) of any kind incurred as a result of the use of any Content posted, emailed or otherwise transmitted via or to the Site.

You may access the Content on the Site only as permitted under these Terms of Use and the Privacy Policy and you agree to not engage in the use, copying, or distribution of any of the Content other than as expressly provided herein.

**You agree not to circumvent, disable, or otherwise interfere with security-related features of the Site or features that prevent or restrict use of any Content or enforce limitations on use of the Site or the Content therein. You may not interfere with or disrupt the Site, or servers or networks connected to the Site, or disobey any requirements, procedures, policies, or regulations of networks connected to the Site, included by using any device, software, or routine to bypass security measures. K-Plex, LLC reserves all rights not expressly granted in and to the Content.**

By submitting Content to K-Plex, LLC, you represent and warrant that:

"you understand you are participating in a public website and that your Content will be available to all other users of the Site; "you are the sole author and owner of the intellectual property and other rights thereto (or have the necessary licenses, rights, consents, and permissions to use and authorize K-Plex, LLC to use all intellectual property and other rights thereto to enable inclusion and use of the Content in the manner contemplated by the Sites and these Terms of Use);

"all ‘moral rights’ that you may have in such Content have been voluntarily waived by you, and you do not require that any personally identifying information be used in connection with the Content that you submit, or any derivative works of or upgrades or updates thereto; 

"all Content that you post is accurate;

"you are at least 16 years old and, if you are a minor, you have obtained the consent of your parent or legal guardian to use the Site and agree to these Terms of Use; and that "use of the Content you supply does not violate these Terms of Use and will not cause injury to any person or entity.

"you are at least 13 years old and, if you are a minor, you have obtained the consent of your parent or legal guardian to use the Site and agree to these Terms of Use; and that "use of the Content you supply does not violate these Terms of Use and will not cause injury to any person or entity.

You also represent and warrant that any content you submit:

"is not false, inaccurate, or misleading;

"does not harm minors;

"does not infringe any copyright, patent, trademark, trade secret or other proprietary rights, or rights of publicity or privacy of any person or entity;

"does not violate any obligations you may have with respect to such Content under any law or under contractual or fiduciary relationships (such as, but not limited to, inside information, proprietary, and confidential information learned or disclosed as part of employment relationships or under nondisclosure agreements);

"does not violate any law, statute, ordinance, or regulation (including, but not limited to, those governing export control, consumer protection, unfair competition, antidiscrimination, or false advertising);

"is not or would not reasonably be considered to be, unlawful, harmful, defamatory, libelous, vulgar, obscene, invasive of another's privacy, hateful, racially or religiously biased or offensive, abusive, tortious, threatening, or harassing to any individual, partnership, or corporation;

"is not submitted for compensation or other consideration from any third party; 

"does not include any information that references other websites, addresses, email addresses, contact information, or phone numbers;

"complies in all respects with these Terms of Use, our Privacy Policy, and all Guidelines and Rules;

"is not unsolicited or unauthorized advertising, promotional materials, "junk mail," "spam," "chain letters," "pyramid schemes," or any other form of solicitation; and

"does not contain any computer viruses, worms, or other potentially damaging computer programs or files. 

If your Content includes ideas, suggestions, documents or proposals to K-Plex, LLC through the Site, (a) such Content is not confidential or proprietary and K-Plex, LLC has no obligation of confidentiality, express or implied, with respect thereto; (b) K-Plex, LLC may have something similar to that Content already under consideration or development; and (c) you are not entitled to compensation, payment or reimbursement of any kind for such Content from K-Plex, LLC under any circumstances unless you are otherwise notified by K-Plex, LLC in writing.  

For any Content that you submit, you grant K-Plex, LLC a worldwide, perpetual, irrevocable, royalty-free, transferable right, and license to use, reproduce, communicate, distribute, copy, modify, delete in its entirety, edit, adapt, publish, translate, publicly display, publicly perform, use, create derivative works from, and/or sell and/or distribute such Content and/or incorporate such Content into any form, medium or technology whether now or hereafter known throughout the world without compensation to you. This license will survive the termination of these Terms of Use and your use of the Site.

**Third Party Content and Third Party Sites**

K-Plex, LLC may provide content of third parties ("Third Party Content") or links to Third Party Sites as a service to those interested in this information. These links are provided for your convenience only and you access them at your own risk. K-Plex, LLC does not monitor, approve, or have any control over any Third Party Content or the Third Party Sites and the inclusion of links to Third Party Content or Third Party Sites does not imply any association or relationship between K-Plex, LLC and such third parties. K-Plex, LLC does not guarantee, endorse, or adopt the accuracy or completeness of any Third Party Content or any Third Party Site. K-Plex, LLC is not responsible for updating or reviewing Third Party Content or Third Party Sites. You use Third Party Content and Third Party Sites at your own risk. Third Party Content, including comments from third party users submitted to K-Plex, LLC, does not necessarily reflect the views of K-Plex, LLC.

If you access the Sites via your mobile phone (for example, through an iPhone application), we do not currently charge for this access. 

Please be aware that your carrier's normal rates and fees, such as text messaging fees or data charges will still apply.

All Content that you submit is not confidential and may be used at K-Plex, LLC's sole discretion. K-Plex, LLC may or may not pre-screen Content. However, K-Plex, LLC and its designees will have the right (but not the obligation) in their sole discretion to pre-screen, change, condense or delete any Content on the Site. 

In particular, K-Plex, LLC and its designees will have the right to remove any Content that K-Plex, LLC deems, in its sole discretion, to violate the Guidelines or any other provision of these Terms of Use or is otherwise objectionable. K-Plex, LLC does not guarantee that you will have any recourse through K-Plex, LLC to edit or delete any Content you have submitted. K-Plex, LLC reserves the right to incorporate any Content you have submitted into any account you may have, now or in the future, as a registered user of the Sites. Ratings, written comments, questions, and answers are generally posted within two to four business days. However, K-Plex, LLC reserves the right to remove or to refuse to post any submission for any reason. 

You acknowledge that you, not K-Plex, LLC, are responsible for the contents of any Content you submit. None of the Content that you submit shall be subject to any obligation of confidence on the part of K-Plex, LLC, its agents, subsidiaries, affiliates, partners, or third-party service providers and their respective directors, officers, and employees.  

K-Plex, LLC reserves the right, at any time, without notice, and in its sole discretion, to terminate your license to use the Site and to block or prevent your future access to and use of the Site. 

K-Plex, LLC may access, preserve, and disclose your account information and Content if required to do so by law or in a good faith belief that such access, preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to (i) comply with legal process; (ii) enforce these Terms of Use, (iii) respond to claims that any Content violates the rights of third parties, (iv) respond to your requests for customer service or (v) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of K-Plex, LLC (and its employees), its users, and the public.

© 2018 Coastal Scents. All Rights Reserved.
